

Waddah Abu Kishk

Address : P.O. Box 961888

Amman 11196, Jordan

Marital

status : Married
Nationality : Jordanian
Date of Birth : 24/3/1975

E-mail : <u>waddahak@yahoo.com</u>
Mobile : +962-79-661-5888

+974-5011-0415 Qatar

Objectives :

Hospitality professional with more than 20 years' experience in Operations.

Having worked in several well reputed International Hotels and Resorts chains. My experience spans multiple hotels brands such as Rotana Towers Dubai-UAE were I began building my career, Rotana Amman- Jordan, Starwood Sheraton Amman, Mövenpick Aqaba, Marriott International Le Meridian Amman, Hyatt Regency Aqaba Ayla Resort and Hilton Salwa Beach Resort & Villas in Qatar.

Top notch Hotel Rooms Division, Responsible for overseeing the daily operation of Front office departments, Housekeeping, laundry, Reservation, Spa and Recreation in Five- Star Deluxe Hotels and Resorts.

Pre-Opening, Project Property Manager for Opera Installation.

With huge background in managing all aspects ,performing daily monitoring of rooms inventory, rate and plan availability; ensuring adequate staffing levels for all departments, Front Office, Housekeeping, Laundry, Reservation, Front Desk, Recreation, Operator, Concierge, Valet, Bell desk, Business center, Executive lounge, Recreation and Spa; developing and implementing training and development plans; managing department forecasts and budgets for both line expenses and payroll and ensures smooth processes and high compliance in all the Operation areas.

Experience:

Hilton Salwa Beach Resort & Villas (Qatar)
October 2020 until January 2021

Pre-Opening Resort Director of Front Office

361 Rooms, Suites, and Villas Opera Installation Property Project Manager

- Set Department objectives, work schedules, budgets, SOP's, policies, and procedures
- Recruit, manage, train and develop the entire team
- Oversee the entire Front Office operation to maintain high standards

Hyatt Hotels Corporation June 2019 until March 2020.

Rooms Division Manager at Hyatt Regency Aqaba Ayla Resort, responsible for overseeing the daily operation of Front Office departments, Housekeeping, laundry, Reservation, Spa and Recreation for 286 rooms and suites. Five- Star Deluxe Resort and Hotel.

- Prepare and monitor Room Division budgets and forecasts.
- In conjunction with the Executive Housekeeper, Front Office Manager and Finance, organize purchases (including capital items) for the Rooms Division to meet the expense budget.
- Assist the Rooms Division management team in resolving guest concerns and complaints
- Work closely with the Managers regarding hiring, training, performance managing associates.
- Assist in developing of a training manual and update as necessary. Review key performance targets and adjust as necessary.
- Monitor performance with regards to setting and meeting key performance targets.
- Motivate, train, coach and monitor associates performance to ensure maximum revenue is generated. Ensure associates are informed of and trained on any new policies and procedures.
- Ensure guest service standards are consistently maintained

Rotana Hotel Management Corporation PJSC July 2017 until June 2019

Director Of Front Office at Amman Rotana, 420 Rooms and Suites, responsible for ensuring the operation of the Front Desk, Guest Services centre, Spa & Recreation, Guest Communications, Uniformed Services, Guest relation, Concierge, Valet, Lobby Manager and Duty Managers.

- Insures compliance with established company policies and procedures.
- Providing courteous guest service and responding to guest questions, complaints or requests.
 Recruiting, hiring and terminating Front Office personnel, as required, upon General
- Orienting and training of Front Office personnel.
- Ensuring that supervised personnel are provided with adequate supplies and equipment in good repair for the accomplishment of their assigned duties.

- Providing timely and responsive service to all other departments through coordinated weekly forecasting, good communications.
- Developing and maintaining work schedules for all supervised staff.
- Maintaining labour cost goals established by Hospitality Management Corporation.
- Maintaining timely and accurate files, reservations, room availability calendar and taking necessary action to open or close room availability on the computer
- Assisting supervised staff in their job performance during peak activity periods or as required.
- Maintaining proper credit and accounting procedures and taking appropriate timely action as necessary.
- Maintaining proper employee/employer relations and addressing any question in a timely and open manner, including disciplinary actions, recognition and performance evaluations.
- Auditing and accounting for all guest checks and folios issued. Assist in the day-to-day operation of the hotel front office.
- Supervise the operational of the hotel front desk within hotel guidelines to provide the highest standard of courteous service while permitting acceptable profit levels.
- Assign, coordinate, and supervise work activities of Front Desk Agents, and ensure work is completed to include, shift closings, room deposits, refunds and rebates.
- Train and develop Front Desk Agents, prepare staffing schedules, complete payroll, and monitor labor costs to budget figures.
- Perform house counts and review daily arrivals, identify potential problems with rooms and take appropriate action.
- Provide information and direction to staff to achieve 100% occupancy. Review and resolve dispute accounts and Housekeeping discrepancies.
- Prepare a shift briefing to communicate activities, short take training, and any problems and/or special information to the next shift.

Marriott International (Previously Starwood Hotels & Resorts) April 2015 until July 2017

Front Office Manager at Le Meridian Amman, 440 Rooms and suites, responsible for ensuring the operation of the Front Desk, Guest Services centre, Guest Communications, Uniformed Services, Guest relation, Concierge, Valet, Lobby Manager and Duty Managers.

It should be noted that I was also in charge of the Rooms Division since October 2016.

Mövenpick Resorts & Residences April 2011 until January 2015

Front Office Manager at Mövenpick Resort Aqaba, responsible for ensuring the operation of the Front Desk, Guest Services centre, Guest Communications, Uniformed Services, Guest relation, Concierge, Valet, Lobby Manager and Duty Managers.

Starwood Hotels & Resorts December 2008 until April 2011

Asst. Director of Guest Services at Sheraton Amman Al Nabil Hotel & Towers, responsible for ensuring the operation of the Front Desk, Guest Services centre, Guest Communications, Uniformed Services, Guest relation, Concierge, Valet, Lobby Manager and Duty Managers.

Starwood Hotels & Resorts October 2004 until November 2008

I held several positions at Sheraton Amman Al Nabil Hotel & Towers:

September 2006 until November 2008 Front Desk Manager

October 2004 until September 2006 Night Manager

October 2002 until October 2004 Front Office Shift leader

Rotana Hotel Management Corporation PJSC October 2000 until October 2002

Guest Services Agent (GSA) at Rotana Towers Dubai

EDUCATION:

American Academy for Hotel Management, Jordan

Hospitality Management Diploma

Hospitality Operations Certificate

Rooms Division Management

Introduction to Hotel Revenue Management, June 2012 by Cornell University School of Hotel Administration Strategic thinking, May 2013 by Cornell University School of Hotel Administration

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Essential Management Techniques Jordan, Business Academy July 2013
- Strategic Thinking Course, Cornell University's School April 2013
- Tactical Revenue Management using Strategic Demand Based Pricing. Jordan 2012, IFH Institute for Revenue Management Cornell University's School June 2012
- Certificate of achievement for completing 5 modules
 - Module (1) Create a good team climate
 - Module (2) Sheraton Signature & emotional Intelligence
 - Module (3) Service netting & recovery
 - Module (4) Everything communicates
 - Module (5) Social styles.
- Time and stress management training from 1/Nov 2008 3/Nov at Sheraton Amman through Gabi for training and development.
- Certification from Starwood (Europe, Africa, Middle East) Starwood behavioural interviewing techniques on 9/June/2009
- Training through Harvard Manage Mentor:
 - Managing for creativity and innovation
 - Turn around supervisors to leader.
 - Managing difficult interactions
 - Leading a team, Keeping Teams on Target
 - Delegating, Focusing on your customer
- Service culture training Phase 1, Phase 2
- Everything communicate
- The gift of opportunity
- Up sell program
- Six Sigma 4 Modules:

- Your Field Guide,
- Introduction to Innovation Transfer
- Getting started with innovation Transfer
- IDMAIC: The Five Phases to Import a Transfer Project
- Star Guest Response . Module I & II
- Sheraton Loyalty programme (Starwood Preferred Guest)
- Table top exercise for hotel crisis and emergency

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Apostolos.papatolios@sheraton.com

Apostolos Papatolios, Marriott international GM.

Malrefai@concordedoha.com

Mashhour Refai, Concorde Doha GM.

hmalki@tivolihotels.com

Husam Malki, Banana Island Doha GM.

Nicolas.Gardier@rotana.com

Nicolas Gardier, Hotel Manager, The Palmeraie Rotana Resort Marrakeck

Atieh.hamarneh@rotana.com

Atieh Hamarneh, Cluster General Manager, Rotana Jordan